=Episode 1=
(This rotten Jinxiu City.)
(This rotten world.)
(Wu Lian.)
(You took my virtue)
(and destroyed everything I had.)
(Hongyun Gate)
Is she gonna kill herself?
(Lin Rulan, Yanyu Embroiderer)
You left me with no justice
(County Office)
and no way to redress my wrongs.
You shameless slut!
You lost your virginity before marriage!
You've shamed all of Jinxiu City!
(Hongyun Gate)
Rulan!
Please come down, Rulan!
If you're gonna die, do it fast!
You've disgraced the entire Lin family!
Wu Lian.
You ruined my innocence
and tainted my reputation.
I swear!
With my blood,
I curse you to a brutal death.
(Then let my death)
(bring an end to it all.)
(Wu Lian!)
(I will never forgive you, even in death!)
(When I become a vengeful ghost,)
(I will come for you)
(and drag you straight to hell!)
=The Embroidered Truth=
(Three Years Later)
Smell that?
Do you smell a maiden's scent?
The phoenix descends upon me.
Its scent surpasses any maiden's.
Now, with the phoenix's blessing,
I command all birds to worship me.
No matter how young and beautiful,
they will all bow down to me.
But you will reign supreme
over Jinxiu's embroidery houses forever.
I, Wu Lian,
your humble subject,
(Wu Lian)
thank Your Highness.
(Embroidery House Master)
Your plaque should arrive any minute.
Go receive your reward.
(Situ Wenyue,
Princess Consort Jingyuan)
(Shen Ruoheng, Lady Cheng'en)
Three years have passed.
Jinxiu City hasn't changed one bit.
Wu Lian of Yanyu Embroidery House
presents the "Hundred Birds Worshiping
the Phoenix" embroidered screen
as a tribute to Her Highness.
For your contributions to embroidery,
(Jinxiu City's Finest Embroidery House)
this place is crowned Jinxiu's Finest.
May you thrive like a phoenix on a
parasol tree.
By order of
Princess Consort Jingyuan.
Thank you, Your Highness.
All embroiderers
of Yanyu Embroidery House
(Meng Wan, House Steward)
congratulate you
on your award, Master.
Wu Lian.
Lin Rulan died here three years ago.
And now she's coming back to life.
Today,
I'm the Lin Rulan
who crawled out of hell
to take your life!
Master Wu.
Three years ago today,
Lin Rulan,
an embroiderer from your house,
(Liu Xin, Former Constable)
jumped to her death.
Do you remember?
Liu Xin.
What do you mean by this?
Today is Rulan's death anniversary.
As her closest friend,
how can you celebrate and curry favor?
This is Lin Rulan's handkerchief.
Lin Rulan?
Isn't she dead?
Wu Lian.
I remember every evil thing you did.
I will watch you every second.
Until I send you
to the execution ground.
The Princess Consort orders:
Lady Cheng'en arrives today.
Master Wu,
go measure Her Ladyship's sizes at once.
(Jingyuan Manor)
(Nanny Du, Jingyuan Manor)
Her identity was verified earlier.
Wenyue.
(Jingyuan Manor)
Greetings, Wenyue.
It's been over ten years.
I've missed you so much, Ruoheng.
I've missed you every day too.
I brought two bolts of Moonlight Brocade
from Father
as a gift for you.
(Xiaotao, Lady Cheng'en's Personal Maid)
Xiaotao.
I adored you when I was little.
And you were always the prettiest.
You traveled all this way
just to see me.
It reminds me of
when we played together.
We said we'd marry the same man someday.
And now it's come true.
I'm here
to help you keep the Prince's favor.
It's windy here.
Let's not talk here.
Please enter the manor,
Your Highness, Your Ladyship.
Don't forget,
Master Wu from Yanyu Embroidery House
is waiting to measure
Her Ladyship's sizes.
Yes, of course.
I'm just so happy to see you.
I forgot about the important things.
The nanny just mentioned
Master Wu from Yanyu Embroidery House.
Is he the master of Jinxiu City's Finest
Embroidery House?
That's right.
He'll measure your sizes
and make you a stunning new robe today.
By the Flower Festival,
no one will be more beautiful than you.
Thank you, Wenyue.
With you here,
I would never overstep my place.
If I weren't past my prime...
Don't be sad, Your Highness.
Your grace and beauty
far surpass Lady Cheng'en's.
Don't you think
Ruoheng is acting strangely?
She was spoiled rotten by her family,
proud and arrogant by nature.
I was
the least favored concubine's daughter.
She always looked down on me.
If my ancestors hadn't saved
Lord Cheng'en's life,
she'd never have agreed
to be a concubine.
She's not acting like herself
at all now.
My Lady.
Master Wu has arrived.
I'm Wu Lian,
Master of Yanyu Embroidery House.
I've come to measure your robes by the
Princess Consort's order.
My Lady, your veil has fallen.
Rulan, you must be scared.
No!
Don't be afraid.
Master...
I will be gentle and love you well.
No!
Master!
No, Master!
Louder!
I like to hear you scream.
No, Master!
Master!
What?
Is it my face
that scares you, Master Wu?
No, no.
Your beauty is divine, My Lady.
Then it must be my face
that reminds you of someone you knew.
You jest, My Lady.
I don't know
such a person.
You look pale.
Did I offend you in some way?
Is that so?
I dare not accept such words, My Lady.
Is there anything in Jinxiu City
you dare not accept?
You're being too modest, Master Wu.
I...
I have no idea
what you're talking about, My Lady.
Didn't you once say that in Jinxiu City,
you call all the shots?
And now you're scared?
Did I scare you so much
that you dare not measure my sizes?
Be gentle with your hands.
If the measurements are off
by even a hair,
I'll chop your hands off.
My Lady.
Now,
I have your measurements.
I'll take my leave.
(Wu Lian.)
(This is just the beginning.)
(I'll haunt you like a ghost.)
(Every debt you owe,)
(I will collect with interest.)
Master.
What's wrong?
She's back.
♪Night fades before the dawn♪
♪Old vows still guide my hand♪
♪The past no longer binds♪
♪My heart still shines through dust♪
♪Silent blooms, unchanged heart♪
♪Bare hands weave through the frost♪
♪Shadows linger, rain returns♪
♪Honor crowns my weary soul♪
♪For your faith that never broke♪
♪I shattered all the love I knew♪
♪No regrets, no debts unpaid♪
♪At dusk I walk away alone♪
♪If this tale becomes a storm♪
♪Old shadows fade from sight♪
♪One thought turns into ash♪
♪No future left to write♪
♪If I never fall♪
♪How could this waiting end♪
♪If I bear no scars♪
♪How could I challenge fate♪
♪I knew there was no way back♪
♪Yet I left this hope behind♪
♪For your faith that never broke♪
♪I shattered all the love I knew♪
♪No regrets, no debts unpaid♪
♪At dusk I walk away alone♪
♪If this tale becomes a storm♪
♪Old shadows fade from sight♪
♪One thought turns into ash♪
♪No future left to write♪
♪The lamp is out, you're gone♪
♪Heaven and earth fall silent♪
♪If we meet again someday♪
♪This longing sleeps beneath the snow♪